<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-23T17:00:09-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">THRED Group</title><subtitle>Technology and Human Research in Engineering Design</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Are Teams Teams? And Other Musings on Humpty Dumpty&quot;s Use of Language In The Design World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/KotovskyCaganMcComb-HumptyDumptysUseOf/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Are Teams Teams? And Other Musings on Humpty Dumpty&amp;quot;s Use of Language In The Design World" /><published>2018-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/KotovskyCaganMcComb-HumptyDumptysUseOf</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/KotovskyCaganMcComb-HumptyDumptysUseOf/">&lt;p&gt;This note explores fundamental assumptions of engineering design methodology and theory that are called into question by recent work. This piece is centered around five questions that highlight the assumptions that we explore. These are (1) Are teams teams? (2) Is search good? (3) Are analogies analogous? and (4) Is novelty novel? (5) Is fixation fixated?  Our intent is to generate critical discourse around these topics and encourage the community to continue to challenge underlying assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>J. Cagan</name></author><summary type="html">This note explores fundamental assumptions of engineering design methodology and theory that are called into question by recent work. This piece is centered around five questions that highlight the assumptions that we explore. These are (1) Are teams teams? (2) Is search good? (3) Are analogies analogous? and (4) Is novelty novel? (5) Is fixation fixated? Our intent is to generate critical discourse around these topics and encourage the community to continue to challenge underlying assumptions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Us Versus Me: An Analysis of Team Process and Performance in Distributed Data Science Challenges</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/MaierDeFrancoMcComb-UsVersusMeAn/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Us Versus Me: An Analysis of Team Process and Performance in Distributed Data Science Challenges" /><published>2018-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/MaierDeFrancoMcComb-UsVersusMeAn</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/MaierDeFrancoMcComb-UsVersusMeAn/">&lt;p&gt;Crowdsourced competitions have seen increased used for software development and data science, and platforms often encourage teamwork between participants. This is unsurprising - teams are ubiquitous, woven into the fabric of engineering and design. Often, it is assumed that teams are better at solving problems than individuals working independently. However, recent work in engineering, design, and psychology has indicated that teams may not be the problem-solving panacea that they were once thought to be. This work undertakes an analysis of the performance of different team styles and sizes in crowdsourced data science competitions. This work demonstrates that groups of individuals working independently may outperform interacting teams on average, but that small interacting teams are more likely to win competitions. These results are discussed in the context of motivation for crowdsourcing participants, and semantic analysis of forum posts is presented to uncover the internal machinery of both and high- and low-performing teams.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>T. Maier</name></author><summary type="html">Crowdsourced competitions have seen increased used for software development and data science, and platforms often encourage teamwork between participants. This is unsurprising - teams are ubiquitous, woven into the fabric of engineering and design. Often, it is assumed that teams are better at solving problems than individuals working independently. However, recent work in engineering, design, and psychology has indicated that teams may not be the problem-solving panacea that they were once thought to be. This work undertakes an analysis of the performance of different team styles and sizes in crowdsourced data science competitions. This work demonstrates that groups of individuals working independently may outperform interacting teams on average, but that small interacting teams are more likely to win competitions. These results are discussed in the context of motivation for crowdsourcing participants, and semantic analysis of forum posts is presented to uncover the internal machinery of both and high- and low-performing teams.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mahandoylemeiselmenold Pullingatthedigital</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/MahanDoyleMeiselMenold-PullingAtTheDigital/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mahandoylemeiselmenold Pullingatthedigital" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/MahanDoyleMeiselMenold-PullingAtTheDigital</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/MahanDoyleMeiselMenold-PullingAtTheDigital/">&lt;p&gt;[Abstract goes here]&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">[Abstract goes here]</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Predicting Part Mass, Required Support Material, and Build Time via Autoencoded Voxel Patterns</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/MurphyMeiselSimpsonMcComb-PredictingPartMassRequired/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Predicting Part Mass, Required Support Material, and Build Time via Autoencoded Voxel Patterns" /><published>2018-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/MurphyMeiselSimpsonMcComb-PredictingPartMassRequired</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/MurphyMeiselSimpsonMcComb-PredictingPartMassRequired/">&lt;p&gt;Additive Manufacturing (AM) allows designers to create intricate geometries that were once too complex or expensive to achieve through traditional manufacturing processes.  Currently, Design for Additive Manufacturing (DfAM) is restricted to experts in the field, and novices may overlook potentially transformational design potential enabled by AM. This project aims to make DfAM accessible to a broader audience through deep learning, enabling designers of all skill levels to leverage unique AM geometries when creating new designs.  To demonstrate such an approach, a database of files was acquired from industry-sponsored AM challenges focused on lightweight design.  These files were converted to a voxelized format, which provides more robust information for machine learning applications. Next, an autoencoder was constructed to a low-dimensional representation of the part designs.  Finally, that autoencoder was used to construct a deep neural network capable of predicting various DfAM attributes.  This work demonstrates a novel foray towards a more extensive DfAM support system that supports designers at all experience levels.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>C. Murphy</name></author><summary type="html">Additive Manufacturing (AM) allows designers to create intricate geometries that were once too complex or expensive to achieve through traditional manufacturing processes. Currently, Design for Additive Manufacturing (DfAM) is restricted to experts in the field, and novices may overlook potentially transformational design potential enabled by AM. This project aims to make DfAM accessible to a broader audience through deep learning, enabling designers of all skill levels to leverage unique AM geometries when creating new designs. To demonstrate such an approach, a database of files was acquired from industry-sponsored AM challenges focused on lightweight design. These files were converted to a voxelized format, which provides more robust information for machine learning applications. Next, an autoencoder was constructed to a low-dimensional representation of the part designs. Finally, that autoencoder was used to construct a deep neural network capable of predicting various DfAM attributes. This work demonstrates a novel foray towards a more extensive DfAM support system that supports designers at all experience levels.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Helping Teams Expand the Breadth of Their Solution Space Through Product Dissection: A Simulation Based Investigation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AlzayedMcCombHunterMiller-HelpingTeamsExpandThe/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Helping Teams Expand the Breadth of Their Solution Space Through Product Dissection: A Simulation Based Investigation" /><published>2018-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/AlzayedMcCombHunterMiller-HelpingTeamsExpandThe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AlzayedMcCombHunterMiller-HelpingTeamsExpandThe/">&lt;p&gt;Product dissection has been highlighted as an effective means of interacting with example products in order to produce creative outcomes. While product dissection is often conducted as a team in engineering design education, the research on the effectiveness of product dissection activities has been primarily limited to individuals. Thus, the goal of this study was to investigate the impact of the type(s) of product dissected in a team environment on the breadth of the design space explored and the underlying influence of educational level and dissection modality on these effects. This was accomplished through a computational simulation of 14,000 nominal brainstorming teams generated by a statistical bootstrapping technique that accounted for all possible team configurations. Specifically, each team was composed of four team members based on a design repository of 931 ideas generated by first-year and senior engineering design students after a product dissection activity. The results of the study highlight that educational level, dissection modality and the number of products dissected all significantly impacted the solution space explored by the simulated teams. Specifically, senior engineering students, physically dissecting the product, and dissecting a wider variety of products all positively impacted the solution space explored. However, several interactions drove further differences. The findings presented in this study can lead to a better understanding of how to most effectively deploy product dissection modules in engineering design education in order to maximize the solution space explored.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>M. Alzayed</name></author><summary type="html">Product dissection has been highlighted as an effective means of interacting with example products in order to produce creative outcomes. While product dissection is often conducted as a team in engineering design education, the research on the effectiveness of product dissection activities has been primarily limited to individuals. Thus, the goal of this study was to investigate the impact of the type(s) of product dissected in a team environment on the breadth of the design space explored and the underlying influence of educational level and dissection modality on these effects. This was accomplished through a computational simulation of 14,000 nominal brainstorming teams generated by a statistical bootstrapping technique that accounted for all possible team configurations. Specifically, each team was composed of four team members based on a design repository of 931 ideas generated by first-year and senior engineering design students after a product dissection activity. The results of the study highlight that educational level, dissection modality and the number of products dissected all significantly impacted the solution space explored by the simulated teams. Specifically, senior engineering students, physically dissecting the product, and dissecting a wider variety of products all positively impacted the solution space explored. However, several interactions drove further differences. The findings presented in this study can lead to a better understanding of how to most effectively deploy product dissection modules in engineering design education in order to maximize the solution space explored.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pulling at the Digital Thread: Exploring the Tolerance Stack Up Between Automatic Procedures and Expert Strategies in Scan To Print Processes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/MahanMeiselMcCombMenold-PullingAtTheDigital/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pulling at the Digital Thread: Exploring the Tolerance Stack Up Between Automatic Procedures and Expert Strategies in Scan To Print Processes" /><published>2018-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/MahanMeiselMcCombMenold-PullingAtTheDigital</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/MahanMeiselMcCombMenold-PullingAtTheDigital/">&lt;p&gt;While the combination of 3D scanning and printing processes holds much promise for the field of new product development, problems with repeatability and accuracy have limited the wider spread adoption of 3D scan to print processes. Some studies have explored the errors inherent in higher fidelity scan to print (S2P) processes, yet few have explored the errors in S2P processes that leverage affordable rapid non-contact digitizers. No studies have explored the strategies experts in digital fabrication employ to mitigate geometric and dimensional errors throughout the S2P process. To address these gaps, a controlled study was conducted using data from 27 scans collected with a common off-the-shelf non-contact optical digitizer and a relatively simple workpiece. Additionally, a behavioral study was conducted with 13 experts in digital fabrication; actions were recorded and later analyzed using hidden Markov modeling. The geometric and dimensional integrity of the digital models was found to be significantly out of tolerance at various phases of the S2P process, as compared to the truth model. Larger errors were found more consistently in the beginning of the S2P process, but these errors were not sufficiently filtered out during the remainder of the process. Experts strategies were not beneficial and digital models produced by experts were found to be significantly smaller than truth models, indicating a trend to “over-clean” digital models. Our findings imply that designers leveraging off-the-shelf RE tools may encounter significant barriers when attempting to integrate digitization tools into the design process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>T. Mahan</name></author><summary type="html">While the combination of 3D scanning and printing processes holds much promise for the field of new product development, problems with repeatability and accuracy have limited the wider spread adoption of 3D scan to print processes. Some studies have explored the errors inherent in higher fidelity scan to print (S2P) processes, yet few have explored the errors in S2P processes that leverage affordable rapid non-contact digitizers. No studies have explored the strategies experts in digital fabrication employ to mitigate geometric and dimensional errors throughout the S2P process. To address these gaps, a controlled study was conducted using data from 27 scans collected with a common off-the-shelf non-contact optical digitizer and a relatively simple workpiece. Additionally, a behavioral study was conducted with 13 experts in digital fabrication; actions were recorded and later analyzed using hidden Markov modeling. The geometric and dimensional integrity of the digital models was found to be significantly out of tolerance at various phases of the S2P process, as compared to the truth model. Larger errors were found more consistently in the beginning of the S2P process, but these errors were not sufficiently filtered out during the remainder of the process. Experts strategies were not beneficial and digital models produced by experts were found to be significantly smaller than truth models, indicating a trend to “over-clean” digital models. Our findings imply that designers leveraging off-the-shelf RE tools may encounter significant barriers when attempting to integrate digitization tools into the design process.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Opportunities for Natural Language Processing in Qualitative Engineering Education Research: Two Examples</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/BerdanierBakerWangMcComb-OpportunitiesForNaturalLanguage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Opportunities for Natural Language Processing in Qualitative Engineering Education Research: Two Examples" /><published>2018-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/BerdanierBakerWangMcComb-OpportunitiesForNaturalLanguage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/BerdanierBakerWangMcComb-OpportunitiesForNaturalLanguage/">&lt;p&gt;This research full paper proposes opportunities to expand qualitative and textual data analysis using natural language processing (NLP), and demonstrates opportunities to use NLP in engineering education work in our presentation of two NLP-based projects as examples of how NLP can be used. The discipline of engineering education frequently employs qualitative data analysis techniques, but fundamentally, the analysis of large corpora of textual documents is limited by researcher’s time. In this paper, we present a brief review literature of how NLP has been used in other qualitative research fields. This portion of the paper is aimed to provide a clear description of NLP for those unfamiliar with machine learning and natural language processing methods. The second part of the paper will provide two brief examples of how NLP is being employed in our research group. Example 1 is a study of engineering résumés, with the intention of being able to calculate the “disciplinary discourse density” based off the engineering language presented in engineering résumés, a technique validated in prior qualitative studies by hand. Example 2 is a genre analysis of engineering literature reviews, seeking to understand the ways in which sentences linguistically build into arguments, such that the task of writing literature reviews might be demystified. This paper will have a methodological impact for researchers attempting to use NLP methods to analyze qualitative data, articulating the opportunities and barriers in using these methods for engineering education research.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>C. Berdanier</name></author><summary type="html">This research full paper proposes opportunities to expand qualitative and textual data analysis using natural language processing (NLP), and demonstrates opportunities to use NLP in engineering education work in our presentation of two NLP-based projects as examples of how NLP can be used. The discipline of engineering education frequently employs qualitative data analysis techniques, but fundamentally, the analysis of large corpora of textual documents is limited by researcher’s time. In this paper, we present a brief review literature of how NLP has been used in other qualitative research fields. This portion of the paper is aimed to provide a clear description of NLP for those unfamiliar with machine learning and natural language processing methods. The second part of the paper will provide two brief examples of how NLP is being employed in our research group. Example 1 is a study of engineering résumés, with the intention of being able to calculate the “disciplinary discourse density” based off the engineering language presented in engineering résumés, a technique validated in prior qualitative studies by hand. Example 2 is a genre analysis of engineering literature reviews, seeking to understand the ways in which sentences linguistically build into arguments, such that the task of writing literature reviews might be demystified. This paper will have a methodological impact for researchers attempting to use NLP methods to analyze qualitative data, articulating the opportunities and barriers in using these methods for engineering education research.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Design Practica as Authentic Assessments in First-year Engineering Design Courses</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/McCombBerdanierMenold-DesignPracticaAsAuthentic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design Practica as Authentic Assessments in First-year Engineering Design Courses" /><published>2018-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/McCombBerdanierMenold-DesignPracticaAsAuthentic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/McCombBerdanierMenold-DesignPracticaAsAuthentic/">&lt;p&gt;This paper describes the design and evaluation of a novel assessment for first-year engineering design courses that is rooted in an authentic design challenge. This approach modifies the traditional written-exam approach typically found in engineering courses, which is inherently inauthentic and cannot easily capture the exploratory nature of engineering design. Our assessment improves alignment with common learning objectives found in first-year engineering design courses and additionally prepares students for the type of case study interviews that are increasingly common for entry-level engineering jobs. To evaluate our assessment, 50 first-year students completed the engineering design self-efficacy instrument once before beginning the assessment and a second time approximately 48 hours later upon completion of a reflection assignment. In addition, students retrospectively reported their perceived change in self-efficacy during the assessment. Analysis shows that students perceived a large retrospective increase in skill level, despite only a small increase in directly measured self-efficacy. These results are analyzed in light of the Dunning-Kruger effect and we posit that the assessment helps to align students’ self-efficacy with their actual skill level. Increased alignment of self-efficacy with skill level may minimize student frustration when encountering challenging tasks in the future, potentially increasing retention of engineering students as well as facilitating the development of lifelong learning attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>C. McComb</name></author><summary type="html">This paper describes the design and evaluation of a novel assessment for first-year engineering design courses that is rooted in an authentic design challenge. This approach modifies the traditional written-exam approach typically found in engineering courses, which is inherently inauthentic and cannot easily capture the exploratory nature of engineering design. Our assessment improves alignment with common learning objectives found in first-year engineering design courses and additionally prepares students for the type of case study interviews that are increasingly common for entry-level engineering jobs. To evaluate our assessment, 50 first-year students completed the engineering design self-efficacy instrument once before beginning the assessment and a second time approximately 48 hours later upon completion of a reflection assignment. In addition, students retrospectively reported their perceived change in self-efficacy during the assessment. Analysis shows that students perceived a large retrospective increase in skill level, despite only a small increase in directly measured self-efficacy. These results are analyzed in light of the Dunning-Kruger effect and we posit that the assessment helps to align students’ self-efficacy with their actual skill level. Increased alignment of self-efficacy with skill level may minimize student frustration when encountering challenging tasks in the future, potentially increasing retention of engineering students as well as facilitating the development of lifelong learning attitudes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Two-Tiered Grammatical Approach For Agent-Based Computational Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/PuentesMcCombCagan-ATwoTieredGrammatical/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Two-Tiered Grammatical Approach For Agent-Based Computational Design" /><published>2018-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/PuentesMcCombCagan-ATwoTieredGrammatical</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/PuentesMcCombCagan-ATwoTieredGrammatical/">&lt;p&gt;Early stages of the engineering design process are vital to shaping the final design; each subsequent step builds from the initial concept. Innovation-driven engineering problems require designers to focus heavily on early-stage design generation, with constant application and evaluation of design changes. Strategies to reduce the amount of time and effort designers spend in this phase could improve the efficiency of the design process as a whole. This paper seeks to create and demonstrate a two-tiered design grammar that encodes heuristic strategies to aid in the generation of early solution concepts. Specifically, this two-tiered grammar mimics the combination of heuristic-based strategic actions and parametric modifications employed by human designers. Rules in the higher-tier are abstract and potentially applicable to multiple design problems across a number of fields. These abstract rules are translated into a series of lower-tier rule applications in a spatial design grammar, which are inherently domain-specific. This grammar is implemented within the HSAT agent-based algorithm. Agents iteratively select actions from either the higher-tier or lower-tier. This algorithm is applied to the design of wave energy converters, devices which use the motion of ocean waves to generate electrical power. Comparisons are made between designs generated using only lower-tier rules and those generated using only higher-tier rules.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>L. Puentes</name></author><summary type="html">Early stages of the engineering design process are vital to shaping the final design; each subsequent step builds from the initial concept. Innovation-driven engineering problems require designers to focus heavily on early-stage design generation, with constant application and evaluation of design changes. Strategies to reduce the amount of time and effort designers spend in this phase could improve the efficiency of the design process as a whole. This paper seeks to create and demonstrate a two-tiered design grammar that encodes heuristic strategies to aid in the generation of early solution concepts. Specifically, this two-tiered grammar mimics the combination of heuristic-based strategic actions and parametric modifications employed by human designers. Rules in the higher-tier are abstract and potentially applicable to multiple design problems across a number of fields. These abstract rules are translated into a series of lower-tier rule applications in a spatial design grammar, which are inherently domain-specific. This grammar is implemented within the HSAT agent-based algorithm. Agents iteratively select actions from either the higher-tier or lower-tier. This algorithm is applied to the design of wave energy converters, devices which use the motion of ocean waves to generate electrical power. Comparisons are made between designs generated using only lower-tier rules and those generated using only higher-tier rules.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Thus, I had to go with what I had”: A Multiple Methods Exploration of Novice Designers Articulation of Prototyping Decisions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/MenoldBerdanierMcCombHockerGardner-ThusIHadTo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&quot;Thus, I had to go with what I had&quot;: A Multiple Methods Exploration of Novice Designers Articulation of Prototyping Decisions
" /><published>2018-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/MenoldBerdanierMcCombHockerGardner-ThusIHadTo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/MenoldBerdanierMcCombHockerGardner-ThusIHadTo/">&lt;p&gt;Effectively communicating designs to stakeholders or end users is a critical step in the design process yet can be a difficult challenge for engineers. Prototypes are unique tools that can enhance communication between these two groups, as prototypes are physical manifestations of the designer’s mental model. Previous work has demonstrated that novice designers often struggle to use prototypes as communication tools. We argue that it is critical that engineering students learn to fully leverage prototypes, and thus the current work sought to understand the relationship between argumentation, prototyping, and design decisions. In order to understand the communication patterns of novice designers during a prototyping task, a controlled study was conducted with a total of 46 undergraduate engineering students. The analysis of quantitative and qualitative data point to the intricate linkages between how students make material decisions and how they justify those decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>J. Menold</name></author><summary type="html">Effectively communicating designs to stakeholders or end users is a critical step in the design process yet can be a difficult challenge for engineers. Prototypes are unique tools that can enhance communication between these two groups, as prototypes are physical manifestations of the designer’s mental model. Previous work has demonstrated that novice designers often struggle to use prototypes as communication tools. We argue that it is critical that engineering students learn to fully leverage prototypes, and thus the current work sought to understand the relationship between argumentation, prototyping, and design decisions. In order to understand the communication patterns of novice designers during a prototyping task, a controlled study was conducted with a total of 46 undergraduate engineering students. The analysis of quantitative and qualitative data point to the intricate linkages between how students make material decisions and how they justify those decisions.</summary></entry></feed>